<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Foodie Diary</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/</link><description>Recent content on Foodie Diary</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright notice</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:26:43 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lemon Butter</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/lemon-butter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:26:43 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/lemon-butter/</guid><description>Ingredients
1 cup sugar 2 tbsp butter grated rind of 2 lemons 3/4 cup lemon juice Method
Beat eggs and sugar together Place all ingredients in saucepan, stir over low heat til consistency of honey Pour into clean sterilised jars</description></item><item><title>Cajun Chicken and Roast Veggie Rice Bowl</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/cajun-chicken-and-roast-veggie-rice-bowl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 22:15:31 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/cajun-chicken-and-roast-veggie-rice-bowl/</guid><description>Serves: 2
Ingrediants
3/4 cup basmati rice 200g pumpkin peeled and chopped into 2cm chunks 1 red capsicum sliced into 1cm strips 1 zucchini chopped into 2cm chunks 1 bunch coriander roughly chopped chicken thighs 2 tbls Cajun seasoning 200g Greek yoghurt 1 clove garlic pepitas water 1.5 cups Method
ROAST THE VEGGIES Place the peeled pumpkin, capsicum and zucchini on the oven tray lined with baking paper.</description></item><item><title>Black Bean Sweet Potato Chilli</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/black-bean-sweet-potato-chilli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 21:09:52 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/black-bean-sweet-potato-chilli/</guid><description>Serves: 4
Ingrediants
1 tablespoon plus 2 teaspoons extra-virgin olive oil 1 medium-large sweet potato, peeled and diced 1 large red onion, diced 4 cloves garlic, minced 2 tablespoons chili powder 1/2 teaspoon ground chipotle pepper 1/2 teaspoon ground cumin 1/4 teaspoon salt 3 1/2 cups vegetable stock 400g of canned black beans, rinsed 400g of canned diced tomatoes 1/2 cup dried quinoa 4 teaspoons lime juice serving suggestions:</description></item><item><title>North African Eggs</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/north-african-eggs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 11:39:38 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/north-african-eggs/</guid><description>Serves: 2
Ingredients
Olive oil, for frying 1 onion, peeled and diced 1 red pepper, deseeded and diced 1 green pepper, deseeded and diced 2 garlic cloves, peeled and sliced 1 red chilli, deseeded and chopped 1 tsp cumin seeds 5 ripe tomatoes, roughly chopped (add a pinch of sugar if the tomatoes aren’t quite ripe) 4 eggs Sea salt and freshly ground black pepper To serve
1 tbsp chopped coriander leaves 1 spring onion, trimmed and finely chopped Crusty bread Method</description></item><item><title>Biltong</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/biltong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 10:26:43 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/biltong/</guid><description>Ingredients
2.5 - 5 kg of whole Silverside (not corned) or Topside are best beef, fat and sinew trimmed and cut with the grain into 2 - 2.5cm thick strips 2l of apple cider vinegar or 2l of the cheap home brand brown vinegar 1 - 2 kg very coarse rock salt 1 packet whole coriander seeds 2 packets of dry coriander powder 3/4 cup of brown sugar 1 tsp of coarse black pepper or whole peppercorns crushed roughly in a mortar and pestle 1 tsp of bicarbonate of soda 100 ml worcestershire sauce (optional) Chile flakes (optional) Method</description></item><item><title>Chilled Overnight Chia</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/chilled-overnight-chia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 18:59:01 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/chilled-overnight-chia/</guid><description>Serves: 1
Milk &amp;amp; Honey: Ingredients
1/2 cup old-fashioned oats 1 tbsp chia seeds 1/2 - 1 tbsp honey depending on how sweet you like it milk or unsweetened plant-based milk Milk &amp;amp; Honey: Method
Add the ingredients to a jar Cover and shake to combine Refrigerate overnight Blueberry-Coconut: Ingredients
1/2 cup old-fashioned oats 1 tbsp chia seeds 1/2 - 1 tbsp honey depending on how sweet you like it 3/4 light coconut milk 1/4 tsp lemon zest (optional) fresh blueberries (optional) Blueberry-Coconut: Method</description></item><item><title>Sweet and Sticky Pork Rice Noodles</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/sweet-and-sticky-pork-rice-noodles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 14:10:13 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/sweet-and-sticky-pork-rice-noodles/</guid><description>Serves: 2
Ingredients
pork mince spring onions, finely sliced green beans, ends trimmed and cut in half 125g rice stick noodles 1 large red chilli, finely sliced 1 bunch coriander 1 clove garlic, peeled and crushed 1 tbs sweet soy sauce (kecap manis) 1/4 cup roasted cashews 1 tbs soy sauce olive oil 1 tbs fish sauce 1 tbs seasame oil water, boiled Method
Marinate the pork combine the pork mince, spring onion, half the garlic and 1/2 the sweet soy sauce.</description></item><item><title>Best Pancakes</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/best-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 08:44:59 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/best-pancakes/</guid><description>Serves: 2 (about 8 pancakes)
Ingredients
3/4 cup milk 2 tbsp white vinegar (lemon juice will work in place of the vinegar to make the bootleg buttermilk) 1 cup flour 2 tbsp sugar 1 tsp baking powder 1/2 tsp baking soda 1/2 tsp salt 1 egg 2 tbsp butter Method
In a small bowl, stir together milk and vinegar. Allow to sit for five minutes. It will look curdled, and that’is normal.</description></item><item><title>Vegan Compote</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/vegan-compote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 08:33:25 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/vegan-compote/</guid><description>Serves 2
Ingrediants:
8-9 apples (granny smith) some butter sugar depingind on taste, vanilla sugar and/or cinnamon Method:
Peel and cut them, not too small. Melt the butter, add the apples, some sugar (+ vanilla etc) at a moderate temperature if too dry add water lease it for 20-25 minutes Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to &amp;ldquo;brown&amp;rdquo; it a little, it adds a caramel taste</description></item><item><title>Mediterranean Chicken With Herbed Fetta Pearl Couscous</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/mediterranean-chicken-with-herbed-fetta-pearl-couscous/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 14:08:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/mediterranean-chicken-with-herbed-fetta-pearl-couscous/</guid><description>Serves: 2
Ingredients
1 clove of garlic, finely cut 1/2 red onion, finely cut 1 cucumber, cut into half moons 1 bunch of mint, finely cut 1 bunch of parsley, finely cut 1 large chicken breast, cut in half lengthways 1 cup couscous or quinoa dried oregano 50g tomato chutney white wine vinegar Method
Preheat the oven to 200°C/180°C fanforced and bring a medium saucepan of salted water to the boil in a medium bowl, combine garlic and dried oregano and drizzle with oil.</description></item><item><title>1 Minute Chocolate Lava Mug Cake</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/1-minute-chocolate-lava-cake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 07:34:46 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/1-minute-chocolate-lava-cake/</guid><description>Serves: 2
Ingredients
4 tbsp all purpose flour 4 tbsp sugar 3 tbsp unsweetened cocoa powder 1/4 tsp baking powder 1/4 tsp salt 1 egg, beaten 4 tbsp milk Method
Into a small bowl add: flour, sugar, cocoa, baking powder, salt, egg, milk. Mix to combine. Pour mixture into a large sized coffee mug or two smaller coffee mugs. Microwave on high for one minute. If needed {if cake batter is still gooey}, microwave on high for up to an additional 10 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Ma Po Toufu</title><link>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/ma-po-doufu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 07:40:40 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://zacmarcus.gitlab.io/CookingRecipies/posts/ma-po-doufu/</guid><description>Serves: 2-3
Ingredients
Silken Tofu: 1 lb 4 oz or 567 g Pork: 100 to 250 g (optional) Chili Oil: 2 tsp Fermented Black Beans: 2 tbsp Dou Ban Jiang: 2 1/2 tbsp Red Pepper Powder/Chili Powder: 1 tbsp Ginger: 1 1/2 tsp Garlic: 4 to 5 cloves or 1 1/2 tbsp Spring Onion: 3 sprigs Soy Sauce: 1 tsp Sesame Oil: 1 tsp Chicken/Vegetable Stock or Water: 1 cup or 237 mL Potato Starch: 1 tsp Water: 1 tsp Method</description></item></channel></rss>